A Guide to the Governor Mark R. Warner, Press Office records, 2001-2006 (bulk 2002-2006)
Library of Virginia
- Series IV. Press material, 2001-2006 (Accession 42626).
  - Reference material--Budget and tax, 2002-2005 (2 of 4) (Box 72, Folder 15)
  - Reference material--Budget and tax, 2002-2005 (3 of 4) (Box 72, Folder 16)
  - Reference material--Budget and tax, 2002-2005 (4 of 4) (Box 72, Folder 17)
  - Reference material--Commission on Efficiency and Effectiveness, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 18)
  - Reference material--DNA, 2004-2005 (Box 72, Folder 19)
  - Reference material--Drought, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 20)
  - Reference material--Eavesdropping scandal, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 21)
  - Reference material--Economic Analysis of Governor Warner's Budget and Tax Reform Plan, 2004 (1 of 2) (Box 72, Folder 22)
  - Reference material--Economic Analysis of Governor Warner's Budget and Tax Reform Plan, 2004 (2 of 2) (Box 72, Folder 23)
  - Reference material--Education, 2003-2005 (Box 72, Folder 24)
  - Reference material--Education for a Lifetime program, 2005 (Box 72, Folder 25)
  - Reference material--Executive Issue Brief, Secure Virginia Panel, 2002 (Box 72, Folder 26)
  - Reference material--Executive Issue Brief, Real ID Act, 2005 (Box 72, Folder 27)
  - Reference material--Game and Inland Fisheries, Dept. of, 2005 (Box 72, Folder 28)
  - Reference material--General Assembly, 2004 (Box 72, Folder 29)
  - Reference material--Government Performance Project, 2005 (Box 72, Folder 30)
  - Reference material--Governor's Proposed Amendments for 2004-2006 Appropriation Act (HB 5001), 2004 (Box 72, Folder 31)
  - Reference material--Hurricane Isabel, 2003 (Box 72, Folder 32)
  - Reference material--Jobs for Virginia program, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 1)
  - Reference material--Leadership Summit on Invigorating the Public Sector, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 2)
  - Reference material--Legislative proposals, 2004 (Box 73, Folder 3)
  - Reference material--Miscellaneous, 2001-2005 (Box 73, Folder 4)
  - Reference material--NASCAR Hall of Fame, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 5)
  - Reference material--National Governors Association, 2004-2005 (Box 73, Folder 6)
  - Reference material--Newspaper and magazine clippings, 2002-2005 (Box 73, Folder 7)
  - Reference material--Partnership for Achieving Successful Schools (PASS) program, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 8)
  - Reference material--Pentagon visit and Homeland Security briefing, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 9)
  - Reference material--Philip Morris relocation, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 10)
  - Reference material--Polls, 2002-2004 (Box 73, Folder 11)
  - Reference material--Reconvened Session, 2004 (1 of 2) (Box 73, Folder 12)
  - Reference material--Reconvened Session, 2004 (2 of 2) (Box 73, Folder 13)
  - Reference material--Reconvened Session, 2005 (1 of 2) (Box 73, Folder 14)
  - Reference material--Reconvened Session, 2005 (2 of 2) (Box 73, Folder 15)
  - Reference material--Redistricting, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 16)
  - Reference material--Technology, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 17)
  - Reference material--Virginia Partners in Procurement Steering Committee Update, 2003 (Box 73, Folder 18)
  - Reference material--Virginia Retirement System, Board of Trustees, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 19)
  - Reference material--Virginia Tech, Board of Visitors decision, 2003 (1 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 20)
  - Reference material--Virginia Tech, Board of Visitors decision, 2003 (2 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 21)
  - Reference material--Virginia Tech, Board of Visitors decision, 2003 (3 of 3) (Box 73, Folder 22)
  - Reference material--Virginia Works program, 2005 (Box 73, Folder 23)
  - Speech material--"Ask the Governor," WTOP, 2002 Feb. 26 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Speech material--"Ask the Gubernator," WRVA/VNN, 2002 Feb. 28 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Speech material--Carilion Medical Center groundbreaking, 2002 Mar. 13 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Speech material--Redistricting case statement, 2002 Mar. 18 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Speech material--First 100 Days in Office speech, 2002 Apr. 22 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Speech material--Sabato class presentation, 2002 Apr. 24 (Box 73, Folder 24)
  - Speech material--Eugenics apology, 2002 May 2 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Speech material--Virginia Tech commencement address, 2002 May 11 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Speech material--Bills approved by the 2002 General Assembly statement, 2002 May 17 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Speech material--Higher Education Summit Steering Committee meeting, 2002 May 31 (Box 73, Folder 25)
  - Speech material--Resignation of Vance Wilkins, Speaker of the House, statement, 2002 June 13 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Speech material--Address to the Commonwealth on Additional Budget Reductions, 2002 Oct. 15 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Speech material--Sniper shootings statement, 2002 Oct. 25 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Speech material--Failure of regional transportation referendums statement, 2002 Nov. 5 (Box 73, Folder 26)
  - Speech material--State of the Commonwealth address (various drafts), 2003 Jan. 8 (Box 73, Folder 27)
  - Speech material--State of the Commonwealth address (various drafts), 2003 Jan. 8 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Speech material--ARC budget cuts statement, 2003 Jan. (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Speech material--Virginia Tech Board of Visitors decision statement, 2003 Mar. 13 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Speech material--Vetoes of SB 1123 and HB 1406 statement, 2003 Apr. 23 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Speech material--Tax fairness and the Poor speech, 2003 Dec. 15 (Box 73, Folder 28)
  - Speech material--WAVY interview, 2005 May 2 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--BRAC Commission vote statement, 2005 July 19 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--Board of Game and Inland Fisheries appointments, 2005 July 25 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--Testimony to BRAC Commission, 2005 Aug. 20 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--Hampton Roads Business Leaders Forum talking points, 2005 Oct. 3 (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--Governor's funding of K-12 education talking points, undated (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--Promises Made/Promises Broken speech, undated (Box 73, Folder 29)
  - Speech material--Miscellaneous or unidentifiable, undated (Box 73, Folder 29)
- Series V. Press releases, 2002-2006 (Accessions 40483, 41073, 41964, 42462).
  Press releases are arranged by month and year and contain all official releases furnished to the news media by the Press Office. The 2004 files also contain separate releases pertaining to Governor Warner's public appearance schedule, which can be found at the back of each month's folder.
  - 2002 (Accession 40483)
    - Press releases, 2002 Jan. (Box 74, Folder 1)
    - Press releases, 2002 Feb. (Box 74, Folder 2)
    - Press releases, 2002 Mar. (Box 74, Folder 3)
    - Press releases, 2002 Apr. (Box 74, Folder 4)
    - Press releases, 2002 May (Box 74, Folder 5)
    - Press releases, 2002 June (Box 74, Folder 6)
    - Press releases, 2002 July (Box 74, Folder 7)
    - Press releases, 2002 Aug. (Box 74, Folder 8)
    - Press releases, 2002 Sept. (Box 74, Folder 9)
    - Press releases, 2002 Oct. (Box 74, Folder 10)
    - Press releases, 2002 Nov. (Box 74, Folder 11)
    - Press releases, 2002 Dec. (Box 74, Folder 12)
  - 2003 (Accession 41073)
    - Press releases, 2003 Jan. (Box 74, Folder 13)
    - Press releases, 2003 Feb. (Box 74, Folder 14)
    - Press releases, 2003 Mar. (Box 74, Folder 15)
    - Press releases, 2003 Apr. (Box 74, Folder 16)
    - Press releases, 2003 May (Box 74, Folder 17)
    - Press releases, 2003 June (Box 74, Folder 18)
    - Press releases, 2003 July (Box 74, Folder 19)
    - Press releases, 2003 Aug. (Box 74, Folder 20)
    - Press releases, 2003 Sept. (Box 74, Folder 21)
    - Press releases, 2003 Oct. (Box 74, Folder 22)
    - Press releases, 2003 Nov. (Box 74, Folder 23)
    - Press releases, 2003 Dec. (Box 74, Folder 24)
  - 2004 (Accession 41694)
    - Press releases, 2004 Jan. (Box 74, Folder 25)
    - Press releases, 2004 Feb. (Box 74, Folder 26)
    - Press releases, 2004 Mar. (Box 74, Folder 27)
    - Press releases, 2004 Apr. (Box 74, Folder 28)
    - Press releases, 2004 May (Box 74, Folder 29)
    - Press releases, 2004 June (Box 74, Folder 30)
    - Press releases, 2004 July (Box 74, Folder 31)
    - Press releases, 2004 Aug. (Box 74, Folder 32)
    - Press releases, 2004 Sept. (Box 74, Folder 33)
    - Press releases, 2004 Oct. (Box 74, Folder 34)
    - Press releases, 2004 Nov. (Box 74, Folder 35)
    - Press releases, 2004 Dec. (Box 74, Folder 36)
  - 2005-2006 (Accession 42462)
    - Press releases, 2005 Jan. (Box 75, Folder 1)
    - Press releases, 2005 Feb. (Box 75, Folder 2)
    - Press releases, 2005 Mar. (Box 75, Folder 3)
    - Press releases, 2005 Apr. (Box 75, Folder 4)
    - Press releases, 2005 May (Box 75, Folder 5)
    - Press releases, 2005 June (Box 75, Folder 6)
    - Press releases, 2005 July (Box 75, Folder 7)
    - Press releases, 2005 Aug. (Box 75, Folder 8)
    - Press releases, 2005 Sept. (Box 75, Folder 9)
    - Press releases, 2005 Oct. (Box 75, Folder 10)
    - Press releases, 2005 Nov. (Box 75, Folder 11)
    - Press releases, 2005 Dec. (Box 75, Folder 12)
    - Press releases, 2006 Jan. (Box 75, Folder 13)
- Series VI. Public schedules, 2003-2005 (Accession 42463).
  Public schedules are similar to press releases, except that they specifically advise the media of appearances to be made by Governor Warner. The schedules were released on the Governor's website on a weekly basis, each one covering the Governor's activities from Monday through Friday. Included in the schedules are notes about locations and times, as well as occasional descriptions of the Governor's remarks. The public schedules are arranged chronologically.
  - Public schedules, 2003 Jan.-Feb. (Box 75, Folder 14)
  - Public schedules, 2003 Mar.-Apr. (Box 75, Folder 15)
  - Public schedules, 2003 May-June (Box 75, Folder 16)
  - Public schedules, 2003 July-Aug. (Box 75, Folder 17)
  - Public schedules, 2003 Sept.-Oct. (Box 75, Folder 18)
  - Public schedules, 2003 Nov.-Dec. (Box 75, Folder 19)
  - Public schedules, 2004 Jan.-Feb. (Box 75, Folder 20)
  - Public schedules, 2004 Mar.-Apr. (Box 75, Folder 21)
  - Public schedules, 2004 May-June (Box 75, Folder 22)
  - Public schedules, 2004 July-Aug. (Box 75, Folder 23)
  - Public schedules, 2004 Sept.-Oct. (Box 75, Folder 24)
  - Public schedules, 2004 Nov.-Dec. (Box 75, Folder 25)
  - Public schedules, 2005 Jan.-Feb. (Box 75, Folder 26)
  - Public schedules, 2005 Mar.-Apr. (Box 75, Folder 27)
  - Public schedules, 2005 May-June (Box 75, Folder 28)
  - Public schedules, 2005 July-Aug. (Box 75, Folder 29)
  - Public schedules, 2005 Sept.-Oct. (Box 75, Folder 30)
  - Public schedules, 2005 Nov.-Dec. (Box 75, Folder 31)
- Series VII. Speeches, 2002-2005 (Accession 42465)
  This series contains print-outs of certain speeches made by Governor Mark R. Warner. The speeches include State of the Commonwealth addresses, speeches given at university commencements, addresses of the General Assembly and its committees, and remarks made at other various speaking engagements. Speeches of note include those given during the budget crisis of 2002, and the highly detailed State of the Commonwealth addresses. It appears that some print-outs are either missing pages, or have been cut off at the end. The speeches are arranged chronologically, and are individually identified in the contents listing portion of this finding aid. For additional information on speeches and statements made by Governor Warner please see the files titled "Speech material" in Series IV. Press material.
  - Inaugural remarks, 2002 Jan. 12 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Address to Joint Assembly, 2002 Jan. 14 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - College of William and Mary Charter Day speech, 2002 Feb. 9 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Virginia Polytechnic and State University commencement, 2002 May 11 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Virginia State University commencement, 2002 May 12 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - University of Virginia commencement, 2002 May 19 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Remarks to the Board of Education, 2002 May 23 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Memorial Day program at McGuire VA Hospital, 2002 May 24 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - U.S.S. Texas Keel Laying Ceremony, undated (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Remarks to the Joint Money Committees, 2002 Aug. 19 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Governor's Housing Conference, 2002 Sept. 12 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Address to the Commonwealth on Additional Budget Reductions, 2002 Oct. 15 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Address to State Agency Heads, 2002 Dec. 3 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - Address to the Joing Money Committees, 2002 Dec. 20 (Box 75, Folder 32)
  - State of the Commonwealth, 2003 Jan. 8 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Testimony Before the House Committee on Government Reform, 2003 Apr. 10 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Radford University commencement, 2003 May 3 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Wytheville Community College commencement, 2003 May 15 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Virginia Military Institute commencement, 2003 May 17 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - George Mason University commencement, 2003 May 17 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - George Washington University commencement, 2003 May 18 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Adult Career Development Center graduation, 2003 June 5 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Virginia Association of Secondary School Principals, 2003 June 23 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Joint Money Committees speech, 2003 Aug. 25 (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - Address to the Joint Money Committees on the Proposed Executive Budget, (2004-2006), undated (Box 75, Folder 33)
  - State of the Commonwealth, 2004 Jan. 14 (Box 75, Folder 34)
  - Joint Money Committees speech, 2004 Aug. 23 (Box 75, Folder 34)
  - Old Dominion University commencement, 2004 Dec. 19 (Box 75, Folder 34)
  - State of the Commonwealth, 2005 Jan. 12 (Box 75, Folder 35)
  - Virginia Military Institute speech, 2005 May 16 (Box 75, Folder 35)
  - Joint Money Committees speech, 2005 Aug. 29 (Box 75, Folder 35)
  - Remarks to the House Appropriations, House Finance, and Senate Finance Committees, 2005 Dec. 16 (Box 75, Folder 35)
  - State of the Commonwealth, 2006 Jan. 11 (Box 75, Folder 36)